Prepare for awesomeness.
Kung Fu Panda is a animation, family, comedy film directed by Mark Osborne.
Chosen by prophecy but doubted by all, Po is an unlikely Dragon Warrior—a clumsy panda thrust
into the world of kung fu as a deadly enemy threatens the Valley of Peace.
Guided by Master Shifu and the Furious Five, Po must embrace who he
is to unlock the power that no scroll can teach.
Po (voice), played by Jack Black.
Tigress (voice), played by Angelina Jolie.
Shifu (voice), played by Dustin Hoffman.
Tai Lung (voice), played by Ian McShane.
Monkey (voice), played by Jackie Chan.
Viper (voice), played by Lucy Liu.
Kung Fu Panda is a 2008 American animated martial arts comedy film directed by John Stevenson and Mark Osborne
and written by Jonathan Aibel and Glenn Berger from a story by Ethan Reiff and Cyrus Voris.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation, it is the first
installment in the Kung Fu Panda franchise.
Starring Jack Black as the voice of the titular character, the film, set in a version of ancient China populated by
anthropomorphic animals, centers on a bumbling giant panda named Po, a kung fu enthusiast living in the Valley of Peace.
When the savage snow leopard Tai Lung is foretold to escape imprisonment and attack the Valley, Po is unwittingly named the "Dragon
Warrior", a prophesied hero worthy of reading a scroll that has been intended to grant its reader limitless power.
The film began development in October 2004, and was initially
conceived as a parody of martial arts films.
However, director Stevenson decided instead to make an action-comedy wuxia film that
incorporated the hero's journey narrative for the lead character.
The project was announced in September 2005.
As with most DreamWorks Animation films, the score for Kung Fu Panda was composed
by Hans Zimmer, on this occasion collaborating with John Powell.
Zimmer visited China to absorb the culture, and used the China
National Symphony Orchestra as part of the scoring process.
Kung Fu Panda premiered at the 2008 Cannes Film Festival on May 15, 2008, and was
theatrically released in the United States on June 6 by Paramount Pictures.
It grossed $632 million on a budget of $130 million, making it the third highest
grossing film of 2008 and the highest-grossing animated film of the year.
It received positive reviews from critics, and was nominated for Best Animated
Feature at the Academy Awards, and the Golden Globe Awards.
The film's success spawned a franchise including three sequels;
the first, Kung Fu Panda 2, was released in 2011.
The film explores themes of martial arts, kung fu, strong woman, china, tiger.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.